Most AI agents and MCP servers are built
to only work with a single user, you.
And a lot of times that's okay. But in
this video, I want to help you move
beyond that. Because here's the thing, a
lot of times we build our AI agents and
we want to scale them to thousands or
millions of users. But also, our agent
needs to be personalized, personal
memory and tools for every single user.
And there is a fundamentally different
way that we have to build our agents if
we want that to actually work because
most agents are built with a single
Gmail account in mind or a single Slack
account or a single rag knowledge base
and that my friend will not scale. Now
I'm using N8N here just because it helps
me demonstrate things very visually for
you. But this is a problem that we have
no matter where we are building our AI
agents and MCP servers. We build
something that needs personalization.
Like in this case, it's a very basic
example of an email assistant agent. And
so we have a couple of tools to manage
our inbox in Gmail. You can obviously
imagine adding a lot more tools to
extend this quite a bit. But the thing
that I'm trying to show you here is that
if we click into any one of these Gmail
nodes, we have our credentials
essentially hardcoded into the agent.
And we see this all of the time. And so
as soon as we want to bring in a second
user, we have to change these
credentials, maybe duplicate the agent.
Obviously not ideal. What we really want
here is for this agent or this MCP to be
able to go through an authorization flow
with the user. So they connect their
Gmail account and the agent will
dynamically use the Gmail account based
on the user interacting with the agent.
We can have that kind of personalization
for memory as well. So we're combining
memory and tools. And the other thing
that'd be really ideal is if the agent
would only go through this authorization
flow when the time comes for it to first
use a Gmail tool on behalf of this user.
These are the kinds of things that are
actually quite challenging to build
ourselves. And trust me, I have tried.
But in this video, I have you covered.
I'll show you how we can build
personalized AI agents that actually
scale. We'll be using Langraph, which is
one of my favorite agentic frameworks.
and they have some awesome features for
long-term memory that we'll be using.
And we'll be also using a platform
called Arcade. Now, Arcade is the key
here for solving the authentication and
scaling nightmare for tools that I can
almost guarantee you wouldn't want to
build yourself because this is what MCP
wishes it had. We can take our AI agents
and we can have them dynamically request
access to user accounts for different
services and we go through an OOTH flow.
So, we have scopes for security and
permissions. We can cache these
credentials going forward so our agents
don't have to ask again. And also we can
build our own tools into the platform.
And then for icing on the cake here, we
also are only asking for permission when
the time comes for our agent to use one
of these services on behalf of our user
for the very first time. It's very
powerful. All right, so I'm going to
give you a really cool demo now of the
agent we're going to build in this video
and it's using langraph and arcade under
the hood. So, I have a basic streamlet
interface that I built for demonstration
purposes. I'm signed into my account
here with my email. This is the Langraph
workflow that I'll show you how to build
later in this video that we have
operating under the hood. So, we have
our agent node. We have its tools and
then we also have this authorization
step whenever our agent needs to get
access to a user's account to use some
tools in arcade for the first time. Now,
I have specifically revoked my access to
a sauna and Gmail so that you can see
the flow for the first time. So, no
connected users in Arcade right now.
I'll go ahead and send in a request.
I'll say, "Grab all my emails in my
inbox and tell me what Cole said because
just for demonstration purposes, I sent
myself an email here. AI SAS ideas using
Arcade." And so, just a few ideas of
platforms that I mean, you could build
without Arcade, but Arcade is going to
solve that huge problem of agent
authorization. And it's just so cool. I
reached out to Arcade and I partnered
with them to bring this video to you
because there really is a whole new
suite of agents and SAS platforms that
we can build thanks to them solving
agent authorization. So yeah, here we
go. So it asks us to visit this URL and
obviously you can make a much nicer UI
here, but I'm just going to go ahead and
click on this link. And so we'll sign in
with our Google account and we will
authorize based on specific scopes what
we want Arcade to do with our Google
account so it can operate on our behalf.
So the authorization is successful. I
can go back here and now in a second.
There we go. So Cole has said in his
email, here are his five SAS ideas. Take
a look at that. And then just to
continue with something simple here, I
can say now look in my SAS ideas project
and tell me which ones I'm missing. So
I'm going to send in this request. I'll
show you what I'm talking about here. So
within my ASA, I have this SAS ideas
project and I'm listing three out of the
five that I sent myself in an email. And
the really cool part here is that now
it's asking for my authorization for a
sauna. And so we can see how whenever we
first need access to a specific tool,
that's when it asks for access. It's not
like we have to do our Gmail and a sauna
and every other tool we connected all up
front. It's just in time authorization.
And so I can click on this link and
we'll go through a very similar process
here. In my case, I already went through
it. So it's just kind of a oneshot
there. And all right. So now in a second
it's going to list out everything in my
ASA and it's going to find the
difference between what it just had here
and then what we have in ASA. There we
go. The ideas that are not currently in
your SAS project is social media growth
agent and calendar and task life
management. And then it asks if I want
to add them to my SAS project so I can
keep going forward with this. But then
the other thing that I want to show you
here is long-term memory. So, I set it
up in a way where I can say remember,
that's my keyword here, telling the
agent to remember something for later
for my user specifically. So, I'm just
saying remember these tasks for later.
So, this is going to use a long-term
memory that is built into Langraph.
There we go. I've remembered these tasks
for later. And I can actually start a
brand new conversation and I can ask it
what are the tasks that I asked you to
remember. All right. So, now leveraging
the long-term memory here because it is
a brand new conversation. There we go.
You asked me to remember social media
growth agent and calendar and task life
manager. There we go. So, we've got
long-term memory. We've got tools
specific to the user with authorization
that's just in time. This is the kind of
personalized agent that we can really
bring to everyone. So, there we go.
We've got long-term memory. We've got
tools that are specific to the user.
Like, if I went and I signed into a
different account here, it's going to go
through the same authorization flow for
Gmail and ASA. I'll have a completely
different set of memory. So, it's not
going to give me the same answer when I
ask this question. This is the kind of
personalized agent that we can bring to
everyone and scale to millions. All
right. So, now that you know what you're
getting yourself into, let's dive into
how we build this agent. So, I'll have a
GitHub repo linked in the description
below where we have the agent there that
you can try yourself. And in the read
me, I've got instructions for setting up
everything. And then what we're going to
go over here is a progression. So, I'm
going to start by covering the
fundamentals, the basics of Arcade and
how we have the Asian authorization
built in. Then, we'll dive into more of
the langraph integration and how that
works with Arcade. And then, finally,
we'll add in the Streaml interface and
long-term memory for the complete agent
that I just demoed for you. And the
thing is, even if you don't end up
building with Arcade, which obviously I
would recommend doing, I reached out and
partnered with them to bring you this
guide for a reason. Even if you don't
build with Arcade, I still want to dive
into the core concepts, the fundamentals
of how exactly we build these kinds of
agents so we can have personalization
that scales to thousands and millions of
users. And so that's what we're covering
in this repository. This is the resource
that I have for you. And getting started
with Arcade is so, so easy. And so you
can sign up. They got a free tier that
can definitely get you started in your
development. And then they have the
documentation. So, I'll link to Arcade
and their documentation below as well.
And man, their documentation just makes
it so easy to get started. So, certainly
poke around with the documentation if
you're interested in using Arcade. They
got a lot here, including a really nice
quick start. But specifically, the
section of the documentation that I'm
really interested in, if I go into
Langchain, they have a guide here using
Langraph with Arcade. And this really is
just a beautiful combination because of
the way that Lang graph helps us build
these agentic workflows that are
necessary to have those authorization
steps kind of just built right into our
agent. And so that's why I'm using
Langraph here. And they show you how to
set up your environment like installing
your pip packages, setting up your
environment variables. And then a lot of
the code that we see here is going to
look very similar to what I'm going to
show you when we dive into our agent.
And what you can do with Langraph is
they have all these preconfigured tools
for things like Firecrawl or Gmail or
Asauna like we saw or Slack or Jira,
Reddit. They have all of these
preconfigured tools that we can bring
into our agents just with a couple of
lines of code. We can also add in our
own tools and MCP servers as well. So
very easy to get everything up and
running with this in mind. And this is
our documentation as our reference
point. Now let's dive into what this
looks like for our agent. All right, so
back to our readme. Let's scroll down to
our progression section cuz I want to
start with the basics of Arcade, laying
the foundation of how we can connect
Arcade to Langraph and have the Asian
authorization for our tools. And I'm
actually pretty excited to dive into
this with you. I've been so focused on
AI coding recently that I haven't had
one of these guides in a while where I
just go through building a script step
by step. So, I'm looking forward to
this. And so, what we're going to be
doing is building out the first version.
And so we're going to actually create
this graph at a very high level and I'll
show you what it looks like to connect
the different tools that we have in
Arcade. And so you can follow the readme
to understand like you know how you
leverage the requirements.ext and the
example to set up your environment. I'm
assuming you have all that taken care
of. And so we can start by importing all
the packages that we need and setting
our environment variables. So we just
need to set our Arcade API key which you
can just do within the settings in your
Arcade dashboard here. And then we need
our OpenAI API key. We're just using GPT
for our model here. And we can define
the exact one we like, like GPT 4.1
mini, and then also the email that we're
using for authorization. And this will
be more dynamic once we get to one of
the more advanced parts of our
progression. And so then what we're
going to do is create an instance of the
tool manager. This is the primary class
in the Arcade SDK where we can define
the tools that we want to bring into our
agent. And so we'll actually do that
right now. So we'll call
manager.gettools.
And then we passed in a couple of tool
kits here for Gmail and ASA just like we
saw in our demo. And so these are the
preconfigured tools. They come out of
the box with Arcade and we can just plug
them right into our agents. It's really
convenient. And then we can also build
our own tools and connect our own MCP
servers as well, which is outside of the
scope of this guide, but I just want to
call that out and you can definitely go
to the documentation to add that as
well. Then once we have all of our
tools, we can call this to lang chain to
basically just take the tools that we
have in arcade and then use their direct
integration to turn it into the tools
that we can then pass directly into a
chat openai instance that we create from
langchain. Now I don't cover lang chain
a lot on my channel. I generally use
pideantic AI for my agent framework, but
this is just what works really well with
arcade and also we're not focusing too
much on lang chain here. We're just
using it to create our connection to the
LLM. And then the rest of the heavy
lifting is going to be done with
langraph. And I definitely cover lang
graph a lot on my channel. So yeah, we
define our chat openaii instance. We
bind the tools that we've created from
arcade. And then we can create our
langraph workflow. So we're just using
an in-memory saver right now. And then
we're calling this create react agent.
So this is a pre-built component from
Langraph. In the next step of our
progression, I'll show you more how we
can actually build the langraph workflow
ourselves. So you see how it works under
the hood. But basically what we're
building here is the flow that we
already saw. So the request from the
user comes into the agent and then the
agent is going to figure out just like
we typically have with AI agents. Do I
need to invoke a tool or can I give the
final response to the user right away?
And so if it doesn't need to invoke any
tools, we'll just go right to end and
it'll give that simple response.
Otherwise, we are either going to go to
tools or to authorization. And it's all
based on if we already have the
authorization for the user's account set
up in Arcade. And so like in my
dashboard right here, my account is
already connected with Asauna and Gmail.
So I've already given the agent the
ability to use the accounts on my
behalf. And so if I were to go in and
ask it to list the emails in my inbox
right now, like just within the Streamla
interface here, then it's going to go
right to the tools node because it
already has that access. So it'll invoke
the tool. the control will go back to
the agent and it'll reason about what
happened and then give the final
response to the user or invoke another
tool. But if I haven't given access yet,
like if I start with a new account or I
go back in the dashboard and I revoke
the access here, then it has to go to
the authorization step first. So it'll
get the authorization for my Gmail
account or my Jira account, whatever,
then go to the tool node, invoke that
tool, then go back to my agent. And so
this is very much like our usual AI
agent flow that we have and we've seen
before, I've covered it on my channel.
It's just we have this one extra node
here for authorization. So it's a very
simple addition, but it unlocks this
whole new world of possibilities for
personalized agents that can scale to
thousands of users. And so this is what
we're building here. And so we create
the React agent. We pass in the tools
and the model. And then we're going to
define our configuration. And so this is
everything that we're passing into the
lang graph flow and then we'll just go
ahead and call it. So it's just
graph.stream. We pass in the user input
and our configuration and we just print
out everything that we get back from the
graph. And then the last thing that
we'll dive into more as we continue here
as well is we have the whole concept of
interrupts in langraph. And so
specifically when we reach the
authorization node, we actually have to
pause the graph entirely because we need
to wait for the user to authorize the
agent to access their Gmail account or
whatever that might be. And so Arcade
has this direct integration with Lang
Graph where whenever we hit this stage,
it's going to pause the graph with this
interrupt and then we would authorize
the account and then the graph needs to
resume and we'll continue on with the
tool call and then getting the final
response from the agent. And for this
first basic implementation, that
automated step where we'd actually
resume the graph after authorization,
we're not doing that here, but we'll see
in a little bit what that actually looks
like. But this is everything that I want
to show you for a very basic
implementation just so that we can see
what it looks like to define the tools
in arcade and then integrate that with
langraph. And so now within my terminal
here, I'll bring this over and we can go
ahead and call Python and then I'll say
arcade one basics.py. So I'll go ahead
and kick this off. Actually off camerara
I did change the question by the way
just to match with our demo from earlier
but it's going to go through the
authorization flow. In my case I already
did give it access to my Gmail account
earlier. So, it's just going to go and
fetch the contents, the five SAS ideas
from the email that I sent myself
already. So, I'll pull my terminal back
up. And there we go. Here are my five AI
SAS ideas. This is looking really good.
And then the other thing that we can do,
I'll show you this really quick. If we
go back into Arcade and I revoke my
access to my email. So, now I I have to
go through the authorization flow again.
And then I clear this. Let me zoom back
out and I'll run the same thing again.
Now, it's not going to give us an
answer. It's instead going to give us a
link because we need access now. So
there we go. So it ends the flow here.
But we'll see in the next iteration when
we get into integrating more with Lang
graph, we can make it so that it'll give
the link, we'll authorize, and then
it'll continue on right away without us
having to rerun anything like we saw in
the demo earlier. Okay. So now on to the
second step of our progression here. I
want to show you more how langraph works
along with arcade. This is where we
really start to understand this pattern
of authorization that's going to apply
no matter the tool or platform that
we're using for agent authorization. And
so I've got the second script that we're
going to go through from scratch. Again,
covering a lot of the same things. So
I'll go a little bit quicker here, but
then talking about more specifically how
exactly we've built up this graph in
Langraph. And the documentation that I'm
referencing for this is the second page
in the lang chain section on user
authorization. And so a lot of the code
that you see and you can reference here
is what we're going to be covering in
our repo. And so starting off with the
same kind of deal here. We're importing
all of our libraries, setting our
environment variables for things like
our Arcade API key and OpenAI API key.
And then we're going to create that same
tool manager. I'm just going to keep
things simple and include the same tools
throughout all these demos here. So
we've got Gmail and ASA again. Going to
convert those to Langchain, build up our
chat, OpenAI, and then I also have this
tool node. This is one of the nodes that
we have in lang graph specifically for
executing a tool once the agent has
decided that it wants to do so. And
we'll see how that plays in with the
rest of the graph in a second here. Then
we can define our workflow. This is
where we define all of the nodes that we
want in our langraph flow and we'll
connect them together at the end as
well. And so starting with our primary
node to call the agent. So going back to
the langraph studio here, we're defining
this purple node right here. And so all
we have to do is take in the messages.
And so we're going to have this with
conversation history as well and we're
going to pass that into the model. So
we're going to call the a stream
function so we can get the tokens out in
real time as they're being streamed from
the LLM. And so we're going to just
write those out like this. And then
we're going to accumulate any of the
tool calls that the agent has decided to
make. And so we build up this list over
time because then if we do have any tool
calls, we have to go to these nodes
here. Otherwise, we'll just give the
final response to the user and go to the
end of the graph. So, accumulated list
of tools right here and then adding into
the message history. So, we're building
up the message history over time, which
we're maintaining as a part of the state
for our LAN graph workflow. So, really
the only state that we're keeping track
of in our graph is the message history.
And then we have a decision node. So, if
the agent has decided to invoke tools,
we have to go to the authorization and
tool nodes. Otherwise, like I said,
we'll just go to the end of the graph.
And so this kind of decision point is
what we're adding right here with this
should continue function. So basically,
we're just checking to see if there are
any tool calls. We'll go to
authorization if we require O. And so
we're basically asking the Arcade tool
manager here, is this a tool that
requires authentication? And do we
already have the authorization for this
user and this account for this tool? If
we do already have all that in place and
we can just invoke the tool right away,
then we'll go right to the tools node,
which is what we've defined right here.
Otherwise, we'll move on to the
authorization step. So, this manager
tells us which one of the two paths we
have to go down here from our agent
whenever we are invoking a tool. And so
then we have our authorize step. And so
this is where we figure out exactly like
what's the URL that we need for for the
OOTH for Gmail or Asauna or whatever
that might be. And then we give that to
the user. So we write this out to the
CLI which we'll run in a second here. Um
or our streamlin application. And then
we're just going to call this manager.we
for off. And so this is where we
integrate directly with the whole
interrupt that we have in langraph. The
whole concept of an interrupt. And so
we're actually going to stop the
execution of the graph here. We're going
to wait for the user to fulfill our
authorization request. Then we'll move
on to the next step of the flow where we
actually execute the tool. we were
waiting on authorization for. And that's
everything. Those are all the nodes that
we have for our graph. And so now we can
just build our graph. So we have a
simple function to do that where we
define the state here which is just a
simple message state because again the
conversation history is the only thing
that we care about here. And then we'll
add our nodes. So we have the agent
tools and authorization. And then we
have all our edges. So we start with the
agent and then from the agent we're
either going to just give the final
response and exit or go to authorization
or tools. And then if we do go to
authorization after we, you know, get
the permission to use the user's
account, then we'll go to tools.
Otherwise, once we go to tools, we want
to go back to the agent because we never
end our workflow execution after
executing a tool. We always want to
invoke the tool and then pass control
back to the agent because then the LLM
is going to figure out like, okay, yes,
my tool call was successful. Now I can
tell the user like, yep, your tool was
successful. Let me give you a summary of
what happened. So we always want to do
that and that's everything for our
graph. So now we can just compile it
with the in memory here. We'll add in
Postgress later in the next example and
we can return our graph and then we just
have a simple main function to execute
our graph very similar to what we did in
the first example here. So that is it.
Now we can go ahead and run the CLI and
test this out. See how it works now
where once we perform the authorization
it'll automatically go on to our tool
call. So now to test out our second
implementation, I have a little CLI
built that I'm not going to dive into
right now. It's very similar to how we
interacted with our lane graph graph in
the first implementation. So I'll go
ahead and run this. And then within my
arcade dashboard, I revoked my access to
aauna again. So we can see what the
authorization flow looks like now that
we have langraph more integrated. So
it'll automatically pick back up after
our authorization. So I can say what
tasks do I have in my SAS ideas project?
and then it'll give me the link to
authorize with a sauna. There we go. So,
I'm going to go ahead and copy this.
Just do it really quickly on my other
monitor here. Okay, so I've done the
authorization and then in just a second
here, it'll start listing out the tasks
that I have. Just those three that I
have in my project right now. And there
we go. In my SAS ideas, I've got these
three. So, this is looking really good.
And because we have the direct
integration with the interrupt here,
we're able to ask for the authorization
and then pick right back up without us
having to re-execute the graph in any
way. All right. So at this point, we
understand the core pattern that we need
to have for agents for agent
authorization. So we can have tools that
are acting on users behalfs with their
services like Gmail and Asa. And so the
last thing that I want to show you how
to add here is long-term memory that is
also custom to each user. So we can have
hyperpersonalized memory and tools
thanks to Arcade. And then some of the
long-term memory stuff that I'll dive
into with Langraph. And so I'll have
this linked in the description as well.
This is the documentation from Langraph
for memory. They cover both short-term
and long-term memory here, which we're
going to be focusing on long-term
memory. So this page right here is
definitely worth a read. And everything
that we're about to implement is coming
from this. And so within the third
example that I have in the GitHub repo
for you, most of our langraph setup here
and our integration with arcade looks
exactly the same. So all this code that
I'm scrolling through right here is
pretty much the same. What really is
different though is we're using
Postgress first of all to store our
checkpointers. That's our interrupts to
handle the authorization. So we know
where we need to pick back up in our
graph. And then also we have this new
concept of a store. The store is for our
long-term memory. And so specifically
the way that I've set it up here, and
you could definitely set up long-term
memory in many different ways. You could
also integrate with me zero, which is a
long-term memory solution that's open
source and I've covered on my channel a
lot. I'm just trying to build something
really simple into Langraph right here.
But specifically, what I've added to
this flow is it's going to check to see
if the keyword remember is anywhere in
the user's message. because if it is,
that is our way to clue the AI agent
that we want to leverage long-term
memory and store this message so it can
pick it back up later. And so if that is
the case, we're going to call this aput
function of the store. And we're going
to add in the data, which is basically
going to be our user request, which we
told it to remember. And this nameace
here, if I go back to where we defined
the namespace, we're specifying the
unique user ID, which in this case, now
that we have streamllet in the mix, and
that this is based off the demo that I
showed you earlier, we actually sign in
with superbase. And so if you take a
look at the example and you set it up
yourself, we define the Superbase URL
and key. So we have Superbase
authentication. So this is actually very
very dynamic where this user ID is going
to be based on the email we use to sign
in with superbase. And so we're storing
long-term memories in our Postgress
database unique to each user. That is
the main thing that we're adding in
here. So when we call our agent, the
main thing that's different is we fetch
those memories and we pass that in as a
part of the prompt to our agent. And
then if we have the remember keyword,
we'll also store the memories from that
last user message as well. And so then I
also built a streamlet interface around
this which I'm not going to dive into
how I configured all of this. You can
take a look at the code if you're
interested. But this is our way to now
interact with the agent that now has
custom tools and memory for each user.
So back over to the stream interface
that I showed in the demo earlier and
I've got instructions in the readme for
spinning this up. I'm going to go ahead
and create a brand new account here. So
I've already done a lot of demoing of
the arcade tools and how the
authorization flow looks like. So maybe
I'll just show the memory really quickly
here. So, I'll make a brand new account
so we can show that we do have distinct
memories for different users. So, I'll
just use one of my throwaway emails here
just to get a new account here with
Superbase. I'll add in my full name. I
will sign up. All right, there we go.
So, I'm logged into a new account and
now I can just say like remember these
tasks. I need to um build a new app and
also uh do my laundry. All right. So,
we're going to go ahead and remember
these tasks. And then I'll show that
like in a brand new conversation, we
have these tasks remembered. There we
go. All right. So, new conversation. Uh,
what tasks did I tell you to remember
for me? All right. So, now it should say
do the laundry and build a new app.
There we go. Yep. Build a new app. Do
your laundry. Perfect. But now, if I log
out of this account and then I log back
into the original one that I was using
for the demo at the start of this video.
So, let me log into this. And now I ask
the same exact question. What tasks did
I ask you to remember? Now, we'll get,
if you remember from the start of the
video, some of the tasks that we had in
the email that I had. There we go.
Social media growth agent, calendar, and
task life manager. So, perfect. We now
have long-term memory individual for
each user. And our agent can access our
individual ASA and Gmail accounts. There
are really powerful ways you can combine
this together as well where the way that
it does things in our ASA and Gmail can
be based off of memories that we gave it
like giving it instructions for it to
remember on how we want it to operate
with our account. So basically every
single user can have a little individual
system prompt essentially for how it
wants the agent to operate for them so
that we don't just have to rely on a
single massive system prompt instructing
the agent on how to do things on users
behalf and they can really get custom
with it as well. So, that's the power of
combining Arcade with long-term memory
and really everything that I had for you
in this video. So, definitely check out
Arcade. There are they are a fantastic
platform. It's free to get started. you
can build these agents that really just
unlock a whole new world of
possibilities for the kind of platforms
that you can build that I mean sure you
could implement agent authorization
yourself but if you really think about
what goes on behind the scenes to manage
the authorization and being able to like
scale the thousands of users and maybe
building a dashboard like this yourself
like Arcade just takes care of so much
for you and combining that with memory
man it is just a gamecher so I hope that
you enjoyed this guide and just getting
an understanding of what this Asian
authorization pattern looks like. And so
if you're looking forward to more things
with AI agents and building these kind
of solutions, definitely give me a like
and a subscribe as well. Thank you for
watching and I will see you in the next